

# - Gizem Ayaz Yegül -

### Full-Stack Web Developer - Experienced Product Owner and Scrum Master

Berlin, Germany • +491723016662 • <u>gizemayazyegul@gmail.com</u> • <u>linkedin.com/in/gayazyegul/</u> • <u>gizemayaz.com</u> • <u>Github</u> • Available to start in June, You can reach us via phone or mail,

9 a.m. to 5 p.m. | Mon-Fri

## Summary

A certified Meta Front End Developer and currently finished Full-Stack Web Developer BootCamp at Ironhack. With an experience as a Scrum Master/Product Owner, possess a unique blend of knowledge and project management skills that are specifically designed for Web Development.

#### **Skills**

#### **Hard Skills**

• HTML • CSS • Javascript • Typescript • React • Bootstrap • Express • Git • RESTful API • Postman • SQL • NodeJS • Handlebars • MongoDB • Figma • Mongoose • Responsive Design • Postman• JIRA • Agile • Scrum • Kanban • User Story • Acceptance Criteria

#### Soft Skills

• Collaboration • Adaptability • Proactivity • Problem-Solving • Mentoring • Teamwork • Time Management •

## **Projects**

#### Project 1: Personal Portfolio

- Description: Crafted a dynamic personal portfolio to showcase my diverse range of projects and skills.
- Technologies Used: Javascript, React, CSS, Flexbox, Bootstrap

#### Project 2: Reframe Fullstack Web Application Hackshow Winner | Ironhack Bootcamp

- Description: Reframe is a mental health application that users can use to enter the gratitude and dairy
- Technologies Used: Javascript, React, CSS, Flexbox, Express, NodeJS, JWT, MongoDB, context API, Vite, react-dom, react-router, RESTful API, Mongoose, React Bootstrap

#### Project 3: Co-Stars Coin-Tracker | Ironhack Bootcamp

- Description: Co-stars is a coin-tracker application, where users can track the current values of coins and their possessed coins. Users can have a dashboard and wallet.
- Technologies Used: Handlebars, MongoDB, Mongoose, Bootstrap, HTML, CSS, Node.js, Express, REST API, Postman

#### Project 4: <u>Javascript Game Project</u> | Ironhack Bootcamp

- Description: The web replica of the game called "AA" on the mobile devices.
- Technology stack: Javascript, OOP, Canvas, DOM manipulation, HTML, CSS

#### Project 5: Little Lemon Restaurant | Coursera Meta Web Developer

- Description: Developed a responsive and dynamic restaurant website featuring table reservation functionality, enabling users to seamlessly reserve tables
- Technologies Used: Javascript, React, CSS, Flexbox, Chakra UI

## **Professional Experience**

## Ironhack, Berlin/Germany • Teaching Assistant

March 2024 - Present

- Actively engaged in daily lab sessions, troubleshooting code and offering personalized assistance to students, resulting in accelerated learning and skill development in **Javascript** and **MERN stack**.
- Facilitated learning sessions and guided students, fostering their understanding of **coding concepts** and best practices in **web development.**

## Usertesting.com, Berlin/Germany • Freelancer Tester

May 2021 - Present

► Utilized user feedback to deepen understanding of UX principles, fostering an acute awareness of user needs and preferences. Demonstrated a keen eye for identifying and swiftly addressing bugs, ensuring seamless functionality of applications.

## Alocai(Altagram), Berlin/Germany • Product Owner

December 2020 - May 2021

- Excelled in technical aspects as a Product Owner, leveraging a strong understanding of **software development principles** and Agile methodologies to drive project success.
- Collaborated closely with developers and the technical development team head to analyze complex technical challenges, ensuring a thorough understanding of project requirements and technical constraints.

## Modanisa, Istanbul/Turkey • Product Owner/Scrum Master

October 2017 - April 2019

- ► Closely work with Web Developers, Mobile Application Teams, and also Backend Developers to analyze the technical capabilities of the codebase for upcoming projects.
- I pointed out stakeholders, and customers' challenges, and also created technical documents. Using **SQL**, and **database** actively.

## Akbank, Istanbul/Turkey • Banking Analytics Intern

August 2017 - September 2017

Spearheaded collaborative efforts with two data analysts and managers to analyze extensive ATM withdrawal data sets, utilizing advanced database querying techniques to extract valuable insights and drive process optimization initiatives.

## **Educational Background & Language Skills**

Full-Stack Web Development • Ironhack / Berlin, Germany

October 2023 - December 2023

**Meta Frontend Development** • Coursera / Berlin, Germany

November 2022 - April 2023

Professional Scrum Master • Scrum.org

April 2019

English C1 • German TELC B1 • Turkish C2

#### **Education**

Physics Engineering • Istanbul Technical University, Istanbul/Turkey

September 2011 - September 2017

- Coursework in Python, C++, and Data Analyses
- ► Thesis: Parallel Programming in Fortran